A Guide to the Papers of Robert Morton Hughes 1767-1959.
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Robert Morton Hughes 1767-1959
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 7
39 Hollinger Flat Boxes; 5 Hollinger Oversized boxes
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Hughes Family, 1976
Accession Number: A76-18
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Morton Hughes was born on September 10, 1855, in the house of his mother's adoptive parents, Gov. John B. Floyd and Sally Preston Floyd at Abingdon in southwestern Virginia. Through his parents, Robert W. Hughes and Eliza Johnston Hughes, he was related to many of Western Virginia's prominent families, including the Prestons, Johnstons, Mortons, and Floyds. Hughes lived in Washington, D.C. and Richmond while still a child but spent most of his early life in Abingdon. He was educated there, largely by private tutors.
Hughes entered the College of William and Mary in 1870 at the age of 15 and graduated with an A. B. degree in 1873. His association with William and Mary would continue throughout his adult life. Hughes served on the college's Board of Visitors from 1893 to 1918 and was rector from 1905 to 1918. He was also an active fundraiser for the college and was instrumental in the establishment of its Marshall-Wythe School of Government and Citizenship. In 1920 his grateful alma mater awarded him an honorary doctor of laws degree while in 1959 the library of the Norfolk branch of William and Mary (now Old Dominion University) was named in his memory.
Hughes also attended the University of Virginia where he studied law and earned a M.A. degree in 1877. After being admitted to the bar this same year, Hughes set up practice in Norfolk, Virginia, where he would continue to work until his retirement in 1920. His specialty was admiralty law. Hughes was elected president of the Virginia Bar Association in 1895 and of the Norfolk and Portsmouth Bar Association in 1907. In 1926 he was appointed by the Governor to a special commission created to suggest revisions to the Virginia constitution.
Hughes was a lifelong Republican, following the lead of his father who had been one of the first prominent Virginians to turn Republican during the Reconstruction period. This affiliation would not prove very rewarding for him. An unsuccessful Republican candidate for congress in 1902 and 1904, Hughes also failed in several attempts to be appointed to federal judgeships, beginning in 1897 when he sought to succeed his father as a judge in the district court at Norfolk, Hughes was a staunch conservative and the last years of his life found him ardently opposing the New Deal in general and Roosevelt's attacks on the Supreme Court in particular.
While Hughes never held elective office he served his community in many other ways. Besides his long tenure on the Board of Visitors of William and Mary, he sat on the Board of Directors of the Norfolk Public Library from 1912 to 1938--he was president after 1921--and was a member of the State Board of Education from 1930 until 1935 when he resigned because of failing health. Hughes was also an active member of Christ Church (Episcopal) in Norfolk where he served as a vestryman from 1884 to 1928.
Hughes' major avocation, especially in later life, was that of amateur historian. His main interest was Virginia history and, within this field, the roles played by members of his own family. He felt particularly duty bound to defend the reputations of two close relatives: Gov. John B. Floyd (1806-1863), his adoptive maternal grandfather, and Gen. Joseph E. Johnston (1807-1891), U.S.A., C.S.A., his maternal great uncle. Johnston had in fact asked Hughes to write his official biography, a work which was published by Appleton in 1893. As a result of his commitment Hughes expended much time and energy writing articles and letters refuting "incorrect" statements by various authors which had directly or indirectly denigrated the careers or questioned the integrity of either man.
Robert Morton Hughes died on January 15, 1940. He was survived by his wife - Mattie L. Smith Hughes, a son - Robert M. Hughes, Jr., and two grandchildren -Robert M. Hughes III and Carolyn Wright Hughes. A second son, Sydney Smith Hughes, had died in 1923.
Scope and Content Information
The Hughes Papers are divided into three major sections. The first section contains Hughes' personal and political correspondence, speeches, literary efforts, small amounts of material related to his legal practice and to his involvement in Virginia political affairs (included is his participation in the Constitutional Commission of 1926-1927), and considerable material about his activities in support of education. Of particular note in this last area are his longtime association with the College of William and Mary (1870-1940) and his service on the State Board of Education (1930-1935).
The second section consists of correspondence and other papers originally belonging to certain of Hughes' relatives. Some of the correspondence goes back to the late 18th century. The major figures are Hughes' father Judge R. W. Hughes (d. 1901). his mother Eliza Johnston Hughes (d. 1908), his adoptive maternal grandfather John B. Floyd, (1806-1863) and his maternal great uncle Joseph E. Johnston, (1807-1891). Judge Hughes was one of the first prominent Virginian's to turn Republican in the post-Civil War Period; Floyd was Governor of Virginia (1849-1852), Secretary of War under Buchanan (1857-1860), and a general in the Confederate army (1861-1863); Johnston was a general in both the U.S. and Confederate armies (1860-1865). Among Hughes' papers are a number of incomplete drafts of Johnston's published war memoirs.
The third section consists of correspondence and other material related to Hughes' extensive activity as an amateur historian. The central topics are the careers of Gen. Johnston and Governor Floyd and after that Virginia and southern history in general.
Contents List
- Personal Correspondence
  - General Correspondence 1872-1877 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence 1878-1889 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence 1890-1899 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence 1900-1939 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, undated (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alice 1871-1873 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mrs. May Brinkley Armat 1931-1938 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Nellie Brinkley 1927-1937 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Frank S. Blair 1885-1886 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Florence Custis 1872 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - L. L. Douglas 1909-1911 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bradford Gilbert 1888-1892 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Judge Nathan Goff 1892-1901 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Armistead C. Gordon 1884-1896 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Robert Goode 1871-1874 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Nannie Greenway 1879-1894 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Annie Hughes 1901 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Floyd Hughes 1880 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 18)
  - R. W. Hughes 1865-1897 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mrs. Elisa M. Hughes 1870-1877 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Agnes Johnston 1901-1902 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Fanny Johnston; Bessie Johnston Graham 1901 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - George Ben Johnson 1878-1912 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - I. Johnston 1891-1892 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Joseph E. Johnston 1866-1877 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - R. S. Jones 1872-1878 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Col. William Lamb 1894-1902 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - L. L. Lewis 1890-1902 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mrs. Mildred Matier 1928-1933 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mildred Matier 1928 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mildred Matier 1929 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mildred Matier 1930-1932 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mildred Matier 1933-1938 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
  - May 1875-1876 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Allan McLane 1909-1933 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
  - James L. McLane 1891-1897 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Robert McLane, Sr.; Robert McLane, Jr. 1891-1892 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mary Floyd Mc Mullen; Lavatilla J. McMullen 1900, 1905 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Kate Mercer; John Mercer 1871-1900 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Jane Michel (Sister of J.E. Johnston) 1891 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Isabel Perkinson; W. H. Perkinson 1887-1904 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Isabel Perkinson Matter at UVA 1903-1905 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Thomas L. Preston 1891-1898 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. John M. Preston; Nellie Preston; Elizabeth Preston Grey 1879-1938 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Harrington Putnam 1900-1905 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sue Taliaferro; J. L. Taliaferro 1880-1898 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Alfred Thom 1885-1905 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Daniel Trigg; Connally Trigg 1886-1901 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 2)
  - L. B. Wharton 1882-1888 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 3)
  - John Sharp Williams (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Selling of books in personal library 1937-1938 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Home Library and Supply Association 1900-1903 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 6)
  - R. W. Hughes, Condolences re death of 1901-1902 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 7)
  - R. W. Hughes, Debts of 1881-1898 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 8)
  - R. W. Hughes, Monument in Abingdon Cemetary 1903-1904 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 9)
  - R. W. Hughes, Memorial Gift to U.S. District Court, Norfolk 1936 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 10)
  - R. W. Hughes, Presentation of Portrait to U.S. District Court, Norfolk 1936 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. R. W. Hughes, Condolences re Death of 1908 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hughes' Estate 1902-1904 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hughes' Estate 1905-1911 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Masonic Lodge Affairs 1888-1896 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Memorial Windows in Abingdon Church 1894-1895 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newbill Matter: Smith Estate (Hughes' Wife's Family) 1899 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Edmund Wadill-Hughes Feud 1898-1917 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Watkins Matter: Morton Estate (relatives of R.W. Hughes) 1900-1902 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
- Financial Records
  - Bills; Tax receipts, etc. (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Real Estate Deeds 1886-1905 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
- Speeches
  - College Period 1870-1879, 3 folders (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6-8)
  - "The Ideal Student" 1892 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Campaign in Norfolk October 23, 1902 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "The Historical Evolution of the Board of Law Examiners and its Influence on Legal Education" 1914 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "The Fighting Editor" 1925-1927, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - "Joseph Eggleston Johnston, Soldier and Man" February 3, 1933 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Historical Topics 1895-1928, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 15 - Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Legal Topics 1892-1923, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Literary Topics 1897-1899, 2 folders (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Literary Topics 1900-1919 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Literary Topics 1921-1925 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Literary Topics 1926-1931 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Political Topics 1902-1920 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 2)
- Writings
  - Memorandum by Mr. Hughes about his writings (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Literary Contributions of R. M. Hughes to the University of Virginia Magazine 1873-1877 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Law of Shipping, chapters 1-3, part of 4 1912 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Writs of Error from the United States Supreme Court to Virginia Courts" 1914 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Joseph I. Doran: A Tribute" 1919 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Fighting Editor" 1927 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Can a State Prescribe a Breathing Spell" 1928 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "A Deserter's Tale" 1931 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Some Letters from the Papers of General Joseph Johnston" 1931 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Joseph Eggleston Johnston: Soldier and Man" 1933 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Sixty Years Ago" 1933 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Civil War or War Between the States" 1935 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "The A.B. Degree and the State Teachers College" 1935 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Robert M. Hughes, His Anthology" Poetry written by Robert M. Hughes (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "The Adoption of Muzzey's History" (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Short pieces (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 18)
- Legal Practice
  - Certification to Practice Law in Virginia 1877 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence 1881-1914 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with E. C. Burks 1886-1895 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Justice John M. Harlan 1896-1904 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with W. M. File (UVA) 1897-1898 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 3)
  - List of Property of Law firm of Hughes and Little 1902 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 4)
  - The Truth Seeker Incident: Correspondence 1913 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Truth Seeker Incident: Copies of Magazine and other material 1912-1913 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Paper on Panama Railroad Company v. Johnson 1924 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 7)
- Politics
  - Correspondence
    - General 1880-1902 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 8)
    - General 1902-1906 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9)
    - General 1920-1924 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 10)
    - General 1925-1937 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Thomas Cadwalader 1928-1929 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 12)
    - R. Walton Moore 1899-1935 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 1)
    - R. Walton Moore (Copies of Speeches) 1935, 1939 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 2)
    - John Garland Pollard (Esp. 1929 Election) 1926-1930 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Editors on Political Topics 1919-1937 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Campaign, 2nd District 1902 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Congressional Campaign, 2nd District 1904 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 6)
    - L. L. Lewis' Effort to get Judgeship 1891 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Magna Carta Association 1922-1924 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Magna Carta Association 1924-1931 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 9)
    - National Association for Constitutional Government 1921-1924 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Sentinels of the Republic 1922-1924 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Sentinels of the Republic 1925-1929 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Sentinels of the Republic 1936-1937 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: U. S. Supreme Court 1934-1935 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: U. S. Supreme Court 1936-1937 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Applications for Judgeships
    - Effort to be Appointed to R.W. Hughes' Judgeship 1897-1898 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence re: Federal Judiciary 1908-1911 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Frederick Brown 1910 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Charles Burlingham 1910 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Nathan Goff 1905, 1910 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Daniel Hayne 1910-1911 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Frank Healy 1910 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Floyd Hughes 1910-1911 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 1)
    - J. C. Pritchard 1908-1910 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Fitzhugh Smith 1910 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Henry St. George Tucker 1909-1911 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Benjamin Thompson 1910 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 5)
    - W. H. White 1905-1910 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 6)
  - General
    - Background Material on Hughes 1910-1911 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Material re: Hughes' Legal Career 1910-1911 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Material re: Congressional Races, 2nd District 1902-1906 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 9)
    - League of Nations: "Democracy and Peace, the Position of the United States after the War" (Speech by Robert B. Tunstall) 1917 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Republicans and the Black Vote in Virginia 1928 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Hughes' Articles re: 1929 Virginia Republican Platform 1929 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper Clippings re: 1929 Gubernatorial Campaign 1929 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 13)
    - U. S. Congress: Copies on Bills 1921-1935 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Papers by Hughes on U. S. Supreme Court 1924-1937 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper Clippings, other Material re: U.S. Supreme Court 1936-1937 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Women's Suffrage 1928 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Political Scrapbook 1902-1903 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Political Scrapbook (1928 Constitutional Convention; 1929 Gubernatorial Campaign) 1928-1929 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings 1901-1937 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Constitutional Commission
    - General Correspondence 1926 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence 1927-1928 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Governor Harry F. Byrd 1926-1929 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Congressman Joseph T. Deal 1928 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence with Robert R. Prentis (Chairman) and M. B. Watts (Clerk) 1926-1928 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with William Meade Fletcher 1926-1928 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Hughes' Paper re: Revision of Constitution 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Articles 1, 2, 4; Bill of Rights; Elections; Legislative Branch 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Article 6; Judiciary 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Articles 7, 9, 11, 12: Organization and Government of Countries; Education; Public Institutions; Corporations 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Articles 13, 14, 15: Taxation and Finances; Miscellaneous Provisions; Future Changes 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Proposals for Revision 1926-1927 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Constitution (including changes initiated by 1926-1927 Commission) 1927-1929 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 3)
- Education
  - College of William and Mary
    - President Benjamin Ewell 1878-1893 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 4)
    - President Lyon Tyler 1901-1906 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 5)
    - President Lyon Tyler 1906-1926 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 6)
    - President J. A. C. Chandler 1921-1933 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 7)
    - President John Bryan 1927-1939 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous College Officials (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Kathleen Alsop 1931-1935 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Dr. James H. Dillard 1920-1934 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Dr. W. A. R. Goodwin 1927-1933 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 12)
    - E. G. Swem (Librarian) 1920-1925 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 1)
    - E. G. Swem (Librarian) 1926-1938 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Margaret Galpin (Acting Librarian) 1935 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Charles Duke 1934-1936 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence 1890-1920 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence 1921-1925 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence 1925-1929 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence 1930-1938 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Douglas Southall Freeman 1920-1921 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Cass Gilbert (re: School's Architecture) 1923 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Thomas Nelson Page 1920-1921 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 11)
    - John G. Pollard 1921-1934 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Alumni Association: Correspondence; other materials 1934-1938 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Boston Alumni Club Plan for College 1934 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Curriculum: Correspondence; other materials 1934-1938 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising: Correspondence 1879-1918 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Fundraising: Correspondence 1920 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Fundraising: Correspondence 1921 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fundraising: Correspondence 1922-1929 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 5)
    - History of the College (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Law School (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Marshall-Wythe School of Government: General Correspondence January-June 1920 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Marshall-Wythe School of Government: General Correspondence July-December 1920 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Marshall-Wythe School of Government: General Correspondence 1921-1927 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Marshall-Wythe School of Government: General Correspondence 1937 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Marshall-Wythe School of Government: Correspondence with Alton B. Parker 1920-1921 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk Branch of William and Mary 1922-1925 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk Branch of William and Mary 1926-1941 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Phi Kappa Alpha Fraternity 1919-1940 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 3)
    - State Financial Support College (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 4)
  - University of Virginia
    - Correspondence 1884-1899 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence 1905-1907 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence 1908-1909 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence 1910-1938 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence re: Coordinate College for Women 1913-1914 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Material re: Coordinate College for Women 1911-1914 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Material re: University of Virginia (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 2)
  - State Education Commission
    - Correspondence; Other Material 1927-1928 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 3)
  - State Board of Education
    - General Correspondence 1929-1931 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence 1932-1935 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with E. Lee Trinkle (President) 1932-1935 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Harris Hart (Superintendent) 1930 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Sidney Hall (Superintendent) 1931-1933 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Sidney Hall (Superintendent) 1934-1936 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Thomas Eason (Secretary to Board) 1930-1931 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Article re: Selection of State Texts 1933 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re: Adoption of Texts 1936-1937 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence; Other Material re: Cooperative Education 1930 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Material 1930-1935 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 5)
- Memorabilia
  - Deputy Grand Master Certificates, Masonic Lodge 1887-1889 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Resolution from Norfolk Public Library Board March 3, 1933 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 7)
  - William and Mary Mementos (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Memorial Volume for Harvey Laird Wilson (Norfolk Ledger Dispatch) 1930 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Memorial Pamphlets to Robert M. Hughes 1855-1940 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 10)